{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"bones","incorrectAnswers":["dialects","trees","dietetics"],"question":"What is Osteology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Iran","incorrectAnswers":["Tajikistan","Kyrgyzstan","Uzbekistan"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Pakistan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"I’ve been a poor man and I’ve been a rich man. And I choose rich every f****** time!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"You're gonna need a bigger boat.\"","\"Keep your friends close, but your enemies closer.\"","\"Open the pod bay doors, please, HAL.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'The Wolf of Wall Street'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Simpsons","incorrectAnswers":["The Flintstones","The Bradys","The Sopranos"],"question":"Which TV Family Adopted A Greyhound For Christmas?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Ill-willie","incorrectAnswers":["Fipple","Oxter","Octothorpe"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'having an unfriendly disposition'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"John Reginald Christie","incorrectAnswers":["John Wayne Gacey Jr","Ted Bundy","Ed Gaine"],"question":"Which notorious murderer, hanged in July 1953, had his story told in the film \"Ten Rillington Place\"? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Robert Mitchum","incorrectAnswers":["James Stewart","Dennis Hopper","John Belushi"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Rev. Harry Powell in The Night of the Hunter?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1947","incorrectAnswers":["1931","1959","1974"],"question":"In which year was the first defibrillator used?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Tarzan","incorrectAnswers":["Spiderman","Scooby Doo","Buggs Bunny"],"question":"What famous character did Edgar Rice Burroughs create?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Lemon","incorrectAnswers":["Mango","Cherry","Banana"],"question":"Which of these fruits is a member of the citrus family?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1952","incorrectAnswers":["1928","1936","1944"],"question":"In which year was the first commercial jet flight?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Democratic Republic of the Congo","incorrectAnswers":["Kyrgyzstan","Turkmenistan","Kuwait"],"question":"Kinshasa is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Forty two","incorrectAnswers":["Twenty","Five","Three"],"question":"What is the atomic number of Molybdenum?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"4 O'clock","incorrectAnswers":["Midnight","9 O'clock","Lunchtime"],"question":"According to The Everly Bros Song \"Wake Up Little Susie\", What Time Did Susie Finally Wake Up?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Niger–Congo","Dravidian","Kra–Dai"],"question":"The language 'Russian' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Coup de grâce","incorrectAnswers":["Tête à tête","Entente cordiale","Merci beaucoup"],"question":"What is the French term for a killing stroke delivered as a merciful act?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"National Geographic","incorrectAnswers":["Time Magazine","Life Magazine","International Geographic"],"question":"In 1984, Steve McCurry took a photo of an Afghan girl for which venerated magazine?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Gabelle","incorrectAnswers":["Ragamuffin","Frankenfood","Gubbins"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'a tax on salt'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Pulp Fiction","incorrectAnswers":["A Streetcar Named Desire","Grease","Gangs of New York"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Jules Winnfield'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Crimean War","incorrectAnswers":["The Georgian War","The Istanbul War","The Odessan War"],"question":"What 19th century war was named after a peninsula in the Black Sea?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Citizen Kane","incorrectAnswers":["Casablanca","Gone with the Wind","The Maltese Falcon"],"question":"In what 1941 movie is the mysterious last word 'Rosebud' whispered by the main character before his death?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Five","incorrectAnswers":["Six","Seven","Eight"],"question":"How Many Players Are In A Basketball Team?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Cobra","incorrectAnswers":["Mustang","Charger","Thunderbird"],"question":"Which iconic sports car designed by Carroll Shelby was produced during the 1960s?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Oasis","incorrectAnswers":["Goldfrapp","Kaiser Chiefs","Jethro Tull"],"question":"Which English rock band formed in Manchester in 1991 released the studio album '(What's the Story) Morning Glory?'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"La Paz","incorrectAnswers":["Belo Horizonte","Buenos Aires","Caracas"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Bolivia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry","incorrectAnswers":["Ilvermorny School of Witchcraft and Wizardry","Durmstrang Institute of Magic","Beauxbatons Academy of Magic"],"question":"In Harry Potter, what is the name of the wizarding school that Harry attends?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Franklin D. Roosevelt","incorrectAnswers":["James Monroe ","John Tyler","George Washington "],"question":"Who was the 32nd president of the USA, in term during the period 1933–1945?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Burrito ","incorrectAnswers":["Taco","Fajita","Quesadilla"],"question":"Which Mexican Dish Translates Into English As Little Donkey?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Vicki Sue Robinson","incorrectAnswers":["Jermaine Stewart","Aqua","The Verve"],"question":"Who had a hit in 1976 with Turn the Beat Around?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Athens","incorrectAnswers":["Rome","Istanbul","Moscow"],"question":"The Parthenon is an iconic structure located in what city?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Leonardo DiCaprio","incorrectAnswers":["Ralph Fiennes","Brian Cox","Kiefer Sutherland"],"question":"Which actor has starred in films including Titanic and The Revenant?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Dracula","incorrectAnswers":["'Salem's Lot","Carrie","World War Z"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line '3 May. Bistritz. - Left Munich at 8.35 p.m. on 1st May, arriving at Vienna early next Morning; should have arrived at 6.46, but train was an hour late.'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Carl Douglas","incorrectAnswers":["Nena","Billy Ray Cyrus","The Verve"],"question":"'Kung Fu Fighting' was a one hit wonder in 1974 by which artist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kentucky","incorrectAnswers":["Arizona","Montana","Idaho"],"question":"Frankfort is the capital of which US state?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Uriah Heep"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Come Together'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Point of View","incorrectAnswers":["Plants or Vegetation","Perform on Video","Play on Vine"],"question":"What do people mean when typing the letters 'POV' in a message on the internet?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Soup pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Shaped pasta","Strand pasta","Ribbon pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is pastina?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Oscar Wilde","incorrectAnswers":["Charles Dickens","G. K. Chesterton","Alphonse Daudet"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Salome'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Theropod","incorrectAnswers":["Sauropod","Pachycephalosaurus","Ankylosaurus"],"question":"What type of dinosaur was the Velociraptor?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Solid Carbon Dioxide","incorrectAnswers":["Solid Methane","Solid Helium","Solid Oxygen"],"question":"What Is Dry Ice?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Houston","incorrectAnswers":["Austin","Dallas","Atlanta"],"question":"Which geographical location was the first word spoken on the moon?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Giovanni Schiaparelli","incorrectAnswers":["Galileo Galiei","Mary Ward","John Herschel"],"question":"Who was the first person to notice \"canals\" on Mars?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"A Motif","incorrectAnswers":["A Chorus","A Verse","A Melody"],"question":"What is a recurring theme in a musical or literary work called?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Dr Pepper ","incorrectAnswers":["Lucozade","Tango","Sunny Delight"],"question":"What soft drink is advertised with the slogan, \"What's the worst that could happen\"?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["Europe","China","South America"],"question":"From which part of the world does eggplant originate?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Turkey","incorrectAnswers":["Syria","Cyprus","Lebanon"],"question":"In Which Country Will You Find The Holiday Resort Bodrum?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["Blue","Gold","Maroon"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of Bolivia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"I Will Always Love You\" by Whitney Houston","incorrectAnswers":["\"SpongeBob SquarePants Theme\" by Painty the Pirate","\"I'm Real (Murder Remix) by Jennifer Lopez and Ja Rule","\"Old Man\" by Neil Young"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"If I should stay, I would only be in your way.\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Syria","incorrectAnswers":["Thailand","North Korea","Puerto Rico"],"question":"Which country's flag fits the description of 'Three equal horizontal bands of red white and black. The white band contains two green stars.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Dies irae","incorrectAnswers":["Danum dos agios","Melita, domi adsum!","Pro bono"],"question":"Which of these Latin phrases translates to 'Day of wrath'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Galilei","incorrectAnswers":["Einstein","Newton","Kepler"],"question":"What is the last name of the 17th-century astronomer known as Galileo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["Yellow","Orange","Green"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of Indonesia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"West","incorrectAnswers":["North","South","East"],"question":"What direction is the opposite of East?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Romanesque","incorrectAnswers":["Baroque","Gothic","Palladian"],"question":"Which medieval architectural style is characterized by large semi-circular arches?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Sea of Love","incorrectAnswers":["The Chain","Ring of Fire","The Man Who Sold the World"],"question":"Which song was originally recorded by Phil Philips and was later covered by The Honeydrippers?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Giraffes","incorrectAnswers":["Rhinos","Deer","Elk"],"question":"__________ are the only animals born with horns.","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Clove ","incorrectAnswers":["Husk","Kernel","Nibbet"],"question":"What is a segment of garlic called?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Woodwind","incorrectAnswers":["Stringed","Brass","Percussion"],"question":"What type of instrument is a bassoon?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"On The Other Hand","incorrectAnswers":["On Top Of Him","Only Truth Out Here","Out The Offensive Harm"],"question":"What does the acronym 'OTOH' stand for in textspeak?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Sandro Botticelli","incorrectAnswers":["Michelangelo","Pablo Picasso","René Magritte"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Primavera\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Scientist who proposed and popularised the theory of evolution.","incorrectAnswers":["Conquistador who claimed Inca lands for Spain.","Influential Christian saint and writer, who shaped much of Western Christian thought.","Victoria era novelist who wrote many popular books."],"question":"Which of the following describes Charles Darwin?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beach Boys","incorrectAnswers":["The Beatles","The Rolling Stones","The Four Tops"],"question":"Who had a hit in 1964 with the song 'I Get Around'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Saturn","incorrectAnswers":["Neptune","Jupiter","Venus"],"question":"What is the sixth planet from our sun?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Mars","incorrectAnswers":["Venus","Jupiter","Uranus"],"question":"Which planet in our solar system has a moon named Phobos that is a similar distance from the planet as Chicago is from London?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Biathlon","incorrectAnswers":["Ski jumping","Skeet shooting","Winter combat"],"question":"In which winter sport do athletes ski cross-country to a shooting range?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Linz","incorrectAnswers":["Stuttgart","Lisbon","Warsaw"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Austria?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Ha*Ash","incorrectAnswers":["The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American Latin pop duo released the album 'Primera fila: Hecho realidad'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Houses Of Parliament ","incorrectAnswers":["Healing Property","Hit Point ","Heavy Produce"],"question":"What does the HP stand for in HP sauce?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Billy Idol","incorrectAnswers":["Billy Eilish","Bill Withers","Bill Bailey"],"question":"William Michael Albert Broad Is The Real Name Of Which Singer?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Qui totum vult totum perdit","incorrectAnswers":["Sapientia potentia est","Ad victoriam","Familia supra omnia"],"question":"Which of these Latin phrases means 'He who wants everything loses everything'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ecuador","incorrectAnswers":["Faroe Islands","Austria","Mongolia"],"question":"Which country's flag fits the description of 'Three horizontal bands of yellow, blue, and red with the coat of arms in the center'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Dolly Parton","incorrectAnswers":["Judy Garland","UB40","Manfred Mann"],"question":"Which artist first recorded 'I Will Always Love You', which was later covered by Whitney Houston?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Smokey and the Bandit","incorrectAnswers":["White Lightning","The Cannonball Run","The Dukes of Hazzard"],"question":"In which 1977 film does Burt Reynolds drive a Trans Am from Georgia to Texas and back?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bangladesh","incorrectAnswers":["Costa Rica","Antigua and Barbuda","Zambia"],"question":"Dhaka is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Perth","incorrectAnswers":["Auckland","Christchurch","Queenstown"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Australia?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Citizen Kane","incorrectAnswers":["Star Wars","Kill Bill: Vol. 1","The Batman"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'After the death of a tycoon, reporters scramble to uncover the meaning of his final utterance.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Percussion","incorrectAnswers":["Woodwind","Brass","Stringed"],"question":"What type of instrument is a maraca?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Colin Firth","incorrectAnswers":["Sean Penn","Billy Bob Thornton","Jean-Claude Van Damme"],"question":"Which actor has starred in both The King's Speech and Shakespeare in Love?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Shaped pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Stuffed pasta","Ribbon pasta","Tubular pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is rotelle?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Tongue","incorrectAnswers":["Heart","Biceps","Deltoids"],"question":"What organ is joined to the hyoid bone?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"You motorboatin’ son of a b****!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"I could do this all day\"","\"I’m the guy who does his job. You must be the other guy.\"","\"I'm gonna make him an offer he can't refuse.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Wedding Crashers'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Dr. Erik Selvig","incorrectAnswers":["Sam Wilson","Drax the Destroyer","The Grandmaster"],"question":"In the Marvel Cinematic Universe, which character is played by Stellan Skarsgård?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Life","incorrectAnswers":["Bell ringing","Rheumatic diseases","Syphilis"],"question":"What is biology the study of?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Plate Tectonics ","incorrectAnswers":["Tectologic Deformation","Terra Firma","Terestial Convection"],"question":"Which Theory Is Used To Explain Continental Drift?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Godfather","incorrectAnswers":["Cabaret","Deliverance","The Emigrants"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1972?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Simon & Garfunkel","incorrectAnswers":["MercyMe","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American music duo released the song 'Cecilia'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Thomas Edison","incorrectAnswers":["Merlin","Richard Feynman","Harry Houdini"],"question":"Who was known as \"The Wizard of Menlo Park\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Pegasus","incorrectAnswers":["Centaur","Griffin","Gorgon"],"question":"Which Ancient Greek mythological creature was a winged horse?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Frankie Goes to Hollywood","incorrectAnswers":["Quiet Riot","Divinyls","Jeannie C. Riley"],"question":"'Relax' was a one hit wonder in 1985 by which artist?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Boardwalk","incorrectAnswers":["The Beach","The Pier","The Promenade"],"question":"In the hit song sung by The Drifters, where are they \"on a blanket with my baby\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Francisco Quevedo","incorrectAnswers":["Miguel de Cervantes","Oscar Wilde","Alphonse Daudet"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Las tres musas últimas castellanas'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Kevin Bacon","incorrectAnswers":["Richard Harris","Anthony Quinn","Hugo Weaving"],"question":"Which actor has starred in both Apollo 13 and X-Men: First Class?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Aerosmith","incorrectAnswers":["AC/DC","David Bowie","Freddie Mercury"],"question":"Who Suggested \"Lets Get Rocked\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"ABBA","incorrectAnswers":["In Flames","HammerFall","Katatonia"],"question":"Which Swedish pop group released the song 'Money, Money, Money'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Heart","incorrectAnswers":["Liver","Lung","Stomach"],"question":"Which organ has a mitral valve and semilunar valves?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"I'm the king of the world!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"That is so fetch.\"","\"This is the day you will always remember as the day you almost caught Captain Jack Sparrow!\"","\"Wait a minute, wait a minute. You ain't heard nothin' yet!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Titanic'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"oceans","incorrectAnswers":["non-terrestrial life","blood serum","the Earth"],"question":"What is Oceanology the study of?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Croatia","incorrectAnswers":["Estonia","Luxembourg","Germany"],"question":"In which country is the city of Zagreb?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Laughing gas","incorrectAnswers":["Cream of tartar","Chloroform","Limestone"],"question":"What is the common name for nitrous oxide?","difficulty":"medium"},